IHOR OKSENTIUK FRONT_END DEVELOPER

ihor.oksentiuk@gmail.com 067-289-75-17

Telegram

LinkedIn

GitHub

Odesa, Lutsk, Ukraine / Remote + Office



Experienced Front-end developer with 1+ years in Fullstack. Skilled in HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Webpack, React, Angular, Node.js, and Express.js. Motivated, stress-resistant, and self-confident. Visual aesthetics has been a lifelong passion. I excel at solving intricate problems that yield visually appealing outcomes, enhancing lives. Opting for full-stack development stems from a curiosity about the complete process and a desire to excel in both frontend and backend. Proficiency in both allows me to execute holistic web app cycles, covering functionality, design, and database integration. I maintain positivity even during challenging or monotonous tasks, uplifting myself and those around me. Have an Intermediate English for communication in foreign teams.

SKILLS

- JavaScript, TypeScript
- React, Redux, Redux Toolkit
- Angular, Angular Material
- Node.js, Express.js
- HTML, CSS (SCSS), Styled Components, BEM
- Wordpress
- GIT, Webpack
- English: Upper Intermediate
- Knowledge of SDLC & STLC
- Agile concepts knowledge (Scrum, Kanban, Scrumban) + Waterfall
- Bug & Task-managers: Jira, ClickUP, Trello
- RxJS
- SQL
- Figma

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer Jan 2022 - present

- Adhered to the company's workflow and reported on the status of tasks in google spreadsheet;
- Attended regular Zoom meetings with the team and actively worked in a team to achieve development goals;
- UI/UX Design, Responsive Design, JavaScript Development, Component-Based Architecture, Web Performance Optimization
- Server-Side Logic, API Development, Database Management;
- · Testing and Debugging;
- Version Control and Deployment;

Gadgets internet market website

Application with animations, adaptive layout, list of phones, tablets and accessories, sliders, pagination, filtering, sorting, routing, authorization, dark and white themes and other interesting features.

• Demo • Github

Bicycle shop landing page

One-page adaptive landing page with a mobile menu, various sections, blocks, and cards.

• <u>Demo</u> • <u>GitHub</u>

Task manager application

A well-styled task manager with the ability to add, delete, mark tasks as completed, switch between completed and active tasks, mark all as completed, and delete all completed tasks. The application also operates using an API where all tasks are stored.

• <u>Demo</u> • <u>GitHub</u>

Currency converter

Application in which you can convert UAH, EUR and USD.

• Github

Internet market

An online store with the capability to add products to the cart, filter, and sort products. Additionally, this application includes an admin panel where you can create new products, edit, and delete existing ones.

• Github

Senior operational officer 2019 - 2021

State Fiscal Service of Odesa region

- Tax control and audits
- · Detection of violations in the field of tax law
- Conducting inspections at enterprises
- · Consulting and informing

Courses landing

One-page adaptive landing page with a mobile menu, various sections, blocks, and cards. There are also two different sliders and pagination here.

• Github

Metricon animated landing

One-page adaptive landing page with a slider and various blocks with different types of animation.

• <u>Demo</u> • <u>GitHub</u>

ADDITIONAL EDUCATION

Mate Academy Apr 2023 - Oct 2023

- Learned advanced features of the layout, <u>JavaScript</u>, <u>TypeScript</u>, <u>React</u>, <u>Redux</u>, and <u>Node.js</u>
- Gained knowledge about <u>How the Web Works (OSI model, HTTP, Encryption, API Interface, and Security in the Web)</u>
- Learned about Algorithms and Data Structures
- Got <u>SQL Basics knowledge</u>

HYS Academy Front-End 2022 - 2023

- Learned how to create web page <u>markup</u>, <u>stylize</u> a web page, and make it <u>responsive</u> for different screen extensions
- Learned how to create a web page using the <u>mobile-first method</u> and work with the <u>SCSS</u> preprocessor. Additionally, I learned about <u>Figma</u>, a web service for designing user interfaces
- Gained experience in bundling projects using <u>Webpack</u> and correctly typing code using <u>TypeScript</u>
- Worked on two pet projects, one of which utilized the Angular framework and the RxJS library
- Learned how to interact with servers and understand how web APIs work

Coursor.Education 2021 - 2022

- Learned <u>JavaScript</u>, including variables, data types and their uses, operators, conditional statements, loops, functions, objects, and more
- Gained knowledge of the working principles of <u>Webpack</u>, which can be used to assemble projects in a high-quality manner
- Gained experience working with the <u>React</u>library and mastered its basic concepts. Lastly, I became familiar with the <u>Redux</u> state manager

EDUCATION

University: Odesa National Law Academy 2014 - 2020

Degree: Master's Degree in Law

Civil and Economic Justice Faculty 2017 - 2018

Course of lectures and seminars in Law in English